Claudio Canales D.

+56 9 67019351 | claudio.canales@usach.cl | ccdonoso.github.io | Youtube - Channel

Presentation

Master in Engineering Sciences, specialized in Mechanical Engineering. Researcher in biomechanics and biomaterials focused on experimental and numerical work, employing numerical methods, solid and fluid mechanics, finite element method, and continuum mechanics. Also, I have a profound interest in **machine learning** and optimization problems. I am a proactive, empathetic and responsible person with great learning capacity and used to work under pressure. I really enjoy working in a multidisciplinary team and continue learning more. Currently, programming finite element modules in the code of the laboratory and implementing reduced order model techniques for faster simulations

EDUCATION

University of Santiago of Chile

Santiago, CL

Master of Science in Engineering, Mechanical Engineering

Aug. 2018 - Dec 2020

- · Scholarship awarded by USACH
- GPA: 4.0 out of 4.0.
- Dissertation: Characterization of Hyperelastic Materials with Metaheuristic Optimization Algorithms (7/7)

University of Santiago of Chile

Santiago, CL

Mechanical Engineering (6 year program)

March. 2016 - Dec 2020

• Maximum Distinction

University of Santiago of Chile

Santiago, CL

 $Mining\ Engineering
ightarrow Change\ of\ career\ to\ Mechanical\ Engineering$

March. 2012 - September 2015

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

October 2019 – Present

Biomaterials - Biomechanics Lab - University of Santiago of Chile

• CBIO 2020 Virtual Conference

October 2020

Chilean Congress of Biomechanics and Biomaterials

Evolutionary Strategies to Characterize Arteries and Stability of Transverse Isotropy

• Computational Mechanics Congress

October 2019

"XVIII Jornadas de Mecánica Computacional 2019"

Characterization of Hyperelastic Models Using Inverse Methods, Based on Metaheuristic Optimization

• XLII Ibero-Latin-American Congress on Computational Methods in Engineering and 3rd Pan American Congress on Computational Mechanics

Nov 2021

Machine Learning for Biological Modelling and Simulation

Evolutionary Strategies and Deep Learning to Characterize Soft Tissue

Evolutionary Algorithms Research Internship

January 2020 – February 2020

Université de technologie de Troyes (Light, nanomaterials & nanotechnologies L2N)

• International Conference on Metamaterials Photonic Crystals and Plasmonics

2021

University of Warsaw - Poland

Symbolic regression in nano-optics: characterization of dispersive materials as a case study

Professional Experience

Teacher of Computational Mechanics

March 2021 - Present

Undergraduate Course at University of Santiago of Chile

Teacher of Computational Mechanics Design

March 2021 – Present

Undergraduate Course at University of Santiago of Chile

Teacher of Complements of Algebra

October 2020 - March 2021

Undergraduate Course at University of Santiago of Chile

Teacher Assistant of Computational Mechanics

March 2018 – July 2020

Undergraduate Course at University of Santiago of Chile

Teacher Assistant of Computerized Design

Undergraduate Course at University of Santiago of Chile

Lions Up Chile Finalist (entrepreneurship contest).

September 2016

March 2018 - July 2020

PROGRAMMING AND SOFTWARE SKILLS

Programming Languages: Fortran, Git, Python, Matlab/Octave, C/C++, HTML.

Software: Latex, Ansys, OpenFOAM, Solidworks, Inventor, Autocad, Fusion 360, SAM, Arduino, Paraview, GiD, Matlab,

Office, EDEM, Ubuntu.

Computational Mechanics Experience

Finite Element Method

Topology Optimization Machine Learning: Deep Learning Specialization Coursera, ROM, Tensorflow

Hyperelastic Modelling: Isotropic and Anisotropic.

Fluid Simulation: Laminar, Tubulent, Non-newtonian.

Metaheuristic Optimization: Genetic Algorithm, Genetic Programming, PSO, Evolutionary Strategies, MOGP.

ABOUT ME

• Full name: Claudio Héctor Canales Donoso

• Chilean ID:18.720.109-8 | Passport: F11725216

• Address: Puerta del sol 180, Las Condes, Santiago, Chile.

• Birth: 11th of April of 1994 | Age: 27 years old

• Languages : Native Spanish | Advanced English

Publications

[1] (Submitted) E. Rivera, C. Canales, M. Pacheco, C. García. D. Macías, D. Celentano and E. Herrera. Mechanical characterisation of the passive mechanical response of the thoracic aorta in chronic hypoxic newborn lambs.

[2] (Manuscripts in Progress) C. Canales, C. García. D. Macías and D. Celentano. Evolutionary strategies to characterize isotropic hyperelastic materials.

[3] (Manuscripts in Progress) C. Canales, E. Rivera, C. García. D. Macías and D. Celentano. Evolutionary strategies to characterize hyperelastic anisotropic materials and a stabilization criterion for transversal isotropy.

ACADEMIC REFERENCES

1.- Prof. Claudio García.

- Head of the Department of Mechanical Engineering.
- University of Santiago of Chile.
- Email: claudio.garcia@usach.cl
- Researchgate Link

2.- Prof. Diego Celentano.

- Associate Professor.
- Catholic University of Chile
- Email: dcelentano@ing.puc.cl
- Researchgate Link

3.- Prof. Demetrio Macias.

- Professor (Assistant).
- Université de Technologie de Troyes.
- Email: demetrio.macias_guzman@utt.fr
- Researchgate Link